Mario Albornoz

 ♥ Berlin, Germany
 ☑ mario.alb.andino@gmail.com
 � Digital-Portfolio Web Page
 in mario-albornoz

 ♠ Mario-Albornoz

Summary

Project-driven Computer Science Student with a record of high performance and working proficiently under pressure. Two years of software development experience, with 9 months of professional work in back-end development mainly with Python. But also have worked on a personal project with Java. In addition, professional experience in other fields outside of software. Looking for an entry-level role eager to learn software development skills and drive organizational success; and set a solid foundation for personal and career growth

Experience

Backend Software Engineer

Berlin, Germany June 2024 – Present

Teach Easy

- o Developed TeachEasy's mobile application back-end completely.
- Provided Basic CRUD features for all sections like: classes, subjects, courses, students, calendar events, assessments, etc.
- Developed and implemented dynamic grading algorithms based on the Austrian school grading system.
- Implemented features such as grades data export. (Exporting report card into excel format)
- Implemented Photo-aided class creation. (User takes a picture of a list with student names, and the back-end recognizes that list, creates the students and enrolls them to the desired class.)
- Managed Server Deployment on a Microsoft ISS server

Medical Spanish Interpreter

Guayaquil, Ecuador

Interpretia- Language Line Solutions

April 2023 - Jan 2024

- \circ Interpreted medical conversations for +2000 patients.
- Represented a more than 90% score in work proficiency throughout the employment period
- Led calls to successful outcomes and communicated the situations in an accurate and precise manner.

In factory product production assistant CoSeitea

Guayaquil, Ecuador April 2023 - Oct 2023

- Served as a key member in the production line.
- Reported inventory status monthly and assisted in warehouse-to-store logistics, reporting, and transportation between three store locations
- Had relevant courses on customer service and product-handling

Product categorization Freelancer

Guayaquil, Ecuador Feb 2022 - April 2022

CoSeitea

- Assisted in the creation of product description cards and product naming. For posting said information on the company's webpage.
- Worked jointly with both store managers and the web developer to keep an organized and concise list of priorities.

Projects

Personal Portfolio

Repository-Portfolio **Ľ** Live Link **Ľ**

- Developed a digital portfolio with 3D interactive objects to showcase experience and skills in web-development
- o Tools Used: React, Vite, Git-pages, TailwindCss, Nodejs, three.js

Auxis Ongoing - No repo available yet

o Its a financial analyst management system for medium size companies. It works by taking the data from electronic billing systems, processing it and transforming it into relevant charts and statistics which will help in the future decision making of that company. It will also integrate basic AI capability like linear regression to make projections based on previous data and other parameters.

o Tools Used: Django, React

Neuracity-Schülerly (Proof of concept)

Nueracity Front-End Repository 2

- AI-powered education management platform for school teachers that automates content creation, assignments, curriculum alignment, and analytics to enhance teaching efficiency. In the future we will implement a protocol called multi model verification pipeline to verify the validity and accuracy of the generated material.
- o Status: On-going, currently working on both front end and backend for material generation.
- Developed by: 3 member team (including myself)
- Tools Used: Django, React, DeepSeek (api)

2 Stage PacMan Java Game

PacMan-Java Repository

- o Developed a two stage Pacman game. Where the first stage is clasic pacman, however once the second stage starts I implemented a simple algorithm to make the tile map move, which increases the difficulty.
- o Tools Used: Eclipse, Java, JFrame

Technologies and Achivments

Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, Html, CSS, SQL, LATEX

Technologies: VsCode, PostMan, Bash, Git, Django, TailwindCss, React, Vite, Sqlite.

Achivements:

- o Winner of Sopra Steria's Internation Student Challenge Germany's National Final
- o Second Place at Gisma-University Teach-Easy Hackaton

Education

Gisma University of Applied Sciences

Oct 2023 - Present

BS in Computer Science

- Relevant Coursework: Data structures and Algorithms, Advanced Programming (With Java), Statistics, Databases and Big Data, Software Engineering, App and Web development.
- Placed second at TeachEasy's Hackaton in 2024

Colegio Menor Campus Samborondon, EC

Jan 2014 - Jan 2023

High-school diploma

- o **GPA:** 4.0/4.0
- o Relevant Coursework: Pre-calculus, AP Calculus.
- Member of NHS (National Honor Society)
- o Varsity Volleyball Captain
- Gathered +3000 cans of food for donations for Canstruction Competition.